Girl students and their parents,
for whom I have come here especially.
You heard the previous speakers,
this is a problem whose seriousness
often goes unnoticed.
I want to tell you with a statistic
that almost
three to four times the number of
deaths that occur in Bihar in a year are due to road accidents. It is
not even appropriate to call it an accident. I
want to call it a road crush. Many times
people mistake an accident for a disaster. In
reality, the collision that occurs on the road is
not a disaster, but somewhere or the other, it is either a
fault of road engineering or the
fault of the user's behavior or there is a
lack in enforcement or
perhaps we are not able to provide good emergency response in the accidents or crushes that happen. There are
many
reasons for this, hence it is appropriate to call it a road crush.
You just saw the banner in front of you
[Prasad],
it has '
Safer Road' written on it. Safe road
means that the road should be such that even if there is a human
error, it should not be so fatal. That
human error should be forgiving.  Our
roads should be of such a nature that for this
we have
started a comprehensive campaign. We are developing a model by identifying the structural faults in the 50 km stretch of Patna city which
cause crushes or the
crushes which occur due to lack of traffic engineering. The same
process is being done in the 50 km
stretch of National Highway of Patna Muzaffarpur
and this model will be
gradually implemented on all the roads in all the districts of Bihar.
Right now in front of you,
this Safe India
Foundation has
surveyed six-seven schools here regarding road safety
and they have suggested how a
safety zone can be established there. I
welcome this. This is such a work,
such a Himalayan task in which the cooperation of all of you
is needed and only then we